# Annoh Karlgusta



annoh.karlgusta@gmail.com



0706684824



linkedin.com/in/annoh-karlgusta

# Summary

I'm a software engineer. From the first time I saw a computer when I was 8, playing computer games, I was intrigued by how it works.

In high school, I couldn't wait to pick computer studies during my subject selections. I lead the class in the exams and practices, with the help of my able teacher.

At the university level, I picked Information Technology. I majored in Software engineering where I learned Data Structures and Algorithms, Systems design, database systems, coding impactful software applications using Java, and collaborating in teams.

I began my technical writing recently, landing me a position at freeCodeCamp.

In the same breathe, I also got into open source, where on GitHub I continue to make my contributions.

I'm a curious person and love learning all about software engineering. I believe in building trust with others and providing solutions to problems.

My core strengths are React.js, Git/GitHub, and Node.js. I also have experience with HTML, CSS, Express.js, Postman, AWS, Bootstrap 4, MongoDB, Playwright, Java, JavaScript, Linux and many more other technologies.

"There can only be one thing. Many things may be important but only one can be the most important." Ross Garber. Software engineering is my one thing.

If you want to reach me for a top secret mission, here is my email: annoh.karlgusta@gmail.com

That's all. Thanks for reading.

# **Experience**



# Software engineering Contributor/Writer

freeCodeCamp

May 2022 - Present (3 months +)

- Creating written tutorials for the freeCodeCamp.org English publication, reaching 1 million+ new
- Teaching 100,000+ Swahili developers how to code through blogs.



#### Software Engineering Officer

County Government of Laikipia

Nov 2020 - Present (1 year 9 months +)

- Edited and published 400+ articles, in less than a year on laikipia.go.ke and on destinationlaikipia.ke

- Contributed to the implementation of digital skills for underserved and excluded farmers ICT4Agriculture project.

# DevOps Engineer

Mother Angela Huruma Hospital

Feb 2020 - Nov 2020 (10 months)

- Designed and implemented the hospital's insurance feature that reduced hospital insurance costs for employees by 90%.
- Trained 3 execs and 10 doctors on the HMIS, increasing efficiency by 50%+ thereby increasing profits by 20%.
- Trained 10 users on the new walk-in patients' feature, increasing system utilization by 90% which increased revenue by 10%.
- Created and managed social media profiles on Facebook, Google maps and Google my business that continues to help 1000s of clients have easier access to the doctors.



#### Volunteer Staff

Walkabout Foundation

Mar 2019 - Feb 2020 (1 year)

- Distributed 40+ wheelchairs to semi-desert area of Turkana for disabled, economically disempowered clients.
- Designed and published 10+ electronic educational materials for the disabled children of UDPL.
- Designed a website for the child company UDPL using WordPress, increasing online visibility by 100%.

#### Education



## Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bachelor of science in Information Technology, Information Technology 2014 - 2018

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

IT Project Management - Indian School of Business UMWRSC8SV7J4



### Managing Project Risks and Changes - UC Irvine

EY7EFJVSN3R8



#### Skills

End-to-end Testing • Docusaurus • php • Express.js • React.js • Representational State Transfer (REST) • TypeScript • Project Management • Kubernetes • YAML